Roberto Carlos Saavedra Baylón

<u>robertocarlos.saavedrabaylon@gmail.com</u> | <u>+34 644983798</u> | <u>linkedin.com/in/rsaavedr</u> | <u>github.com/robertosaavedr</u>

PERSONAL PROFILE

I have just finished my Bachelor's Degree in Applied Statistics in June 2022. I am a very proactive person, I have participated in the US Work and Travel program which allowed me to work for a summer in the United States, also, while in university I have worked as a lifeguard, cleaner, teacher and waiter, which adds to my internships and jobs working with data. In my free time I like to read, travel, lift weights and hike...

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Applied Statistics, Complutense University of Madrid 2018-2022

- Average grade 7.8/10

Exchange Year, National University of Ireland, Maynooth

2020-2021

EXPERIENCE

R Programmer

February 2022 – April 2022

Quental Technologies, Madrid, Spain

- I was hired for a 3 months project with a spanish bank to code in **R**, I was in a team developing software to automate tasks for the Risk Analysts, such as a calculator for the expected monetary loss given a dataset of mortgages.

Data Analyst Intern

October 2021 – January 2022

Instituto de Estudios Fiscales, Madrid, Spain

- Internship in the Ministry of Finance of Spain, regression and descriptive analysis of Tax Income Data using **SAS**.

Data Analyst Intern

November 2019 – October 2020

Faculty of Statistical Studies, Madrid, Spain

- Analysis of data from surveys using **R**, **SPSS** and **SAS**.

Founder and Podcaster

September 2018 – June 2022

Import Coffee, Madrid, Spain

- In our first year of university, a friend and I decided to found a student's association, Import Coffee has gathered dozens of students interested in programming and statistics, we have organized several workshops (web scraping, python, julia...) and created a <u>podcast</u> where I interview people in the data industry.

TECH SKILLS	SOFT SKILLS	LANGUAGES
R PYTHON SQL	COMMUNICATION	ENGLISH: C1 (APTIS)
MACHINE LEARNING	DESIRE TO LEARN	SPANISH: NATIVE
STATISTICS GIT	GROWTH MINDSET	